Here.
And then finally we have
that connection to the damper.
Somewhere around here. Doesn't need to be drawn to scale or anything like that.
Just trying to get a general sense as to where to apply the loading conditions.
So,
essentially we have
the engine
kind of off over here.
Right.
And so the engine weight is just, you know, if we just modeled it as a point mass, it's just
going like that right now.
And so the reactions we'd expect are
that we're getting
in our system, we'd expect that there'd be
probably
forces being applied here.
Forces being applied on the second one.
And force being applied here.
And one force being applied here.
Because that needs to be sitting on the damper, so there's going to be some amount of force
that is, that it's going to carry there. So,
we can start with four forces. I wonder,
I mean, so if we have four forces,
we're not going to have, we should be fine
from a condition, like a boundary condition sort of
perspective. It should be solvable because we'll have the moment equations
theoretically to help us solve out like what's going on
everywhere so we could work out what,
you know, what force is going to be applied everywhere, but it should also be
something that we can design actually for and figure out, you know, maybe we,
maybe with this free body diagram, what we want to do right is we want to figure out
what forces are being applied where, what moments are being applied and stuff like that and then apply
that using the knowledge we can gain from the free body diagram. So,
let's maybe...
I want to ask you a couple of questions that might help you think through the design task.
Go for it.
What are your assumptions for the structural constraints?
My assumptions for the structural constraints are that
we are going to have
assumptions for the constructional constraints.
Can you define what you mean by constructional constraints?
Give me a second.
While that's going I'll just think a bit more about this.
Constructional constraints.
Mm-hmm.
Apply those forces there.
We also have to think about what we're going to model.
The solver requires structural loads and structural constraints.
What are your assumptions for the structural constraints?
Well, my assumptions right now for the structural constraints is that, you know,
in the most basic case, if I just wanted to get jump right into designing it, is that I would need to apply
forces on most of these structure, on basically all of the connection points, and then I would need to model
the bracket connections as fixed connections, and I would want to model the damper as
I guess it could technically...
I mean it's sitting on there, but it's also screwed in, so I would also model that as a fixed connection, I believe,
because it's this actual piece that's going to be kind of damping everything out and potentially moving,
and this shouldn't be moving, this connection shouldn't be moving, so I would model every connection as fixed.
So that's kind of the... those are the assumptions I'm running with currently.
What alternative assumptions might we make about the load case?
Alternative assumptions... well we might need to apply, depending on how I want to solve out this sort of free body diagram,
we might need to apply some moments or other loads that we might not be expecting.
You could, I guess, model the connection at the damper as potentially a pin so that it can slide,
but I... and then say that it's just not really carrying any force, but I don't think that would be accurate to the situation,
but we can see depending on how the design generates, if that is kind of a valid concern or not.
Okay, what will the solver when we specify all preserved bodies as fixed constraints?
What would... can you repeat the question?
Okay, what will the solver do when we specify all preserved bodies as fixed constraints?
All preserved bodies as fixed constraints... what would the solver do if we defined all of the bodies as fixed constraints?
That is a good question, I do not know.
I guess we can go and check and see really quickly.
So if we go into the software here and we open up the Generate Design Study and we create a structural component,
if we say that we need to preserve... well it's a good thing to set this up anyway because we're going to have to do this.
We'll preserve all of these and then if we tell it that we need to design structural constraints,
and we're going to say that... so let's see what happens if we say that all of these are fixed.
Oh right, it's faces that I'm selecting. Okay, let me think about that then.
Well, so the ones that we need to design as fixed then are going to be this face here, this face here, this face here...
I guess we can leave this one floating.
I mean, I'll see if I design this one as fixed as well.
So we've got those fixed, we're not going to assign any obstacle geometry for a second.
We can set the objectives that we're trying to minimize mass, we'll set a factor of safety of two for now.
And then I don't know if I need to set manufacturing or materials to do that sort of previewer, but I'll just do it just to be safe.
Let's say we're doing additive and milling, not unrestricted, okay.
And we have materials, let's just put in one material for now just so that we have it.
We'll put in just like an aluminum, close that up, okay.
So we've set the preserved geometry, we didn't set any obstacle geometry.
We have our objectives, we have manufacturing, we have...
Ah, we didn't add loads.
Let's add in some loads just for fun.
Let's say that on this face, on this face, and on this face, and on...
I guess we can select the top face here.
And let's say that...
Let's say they're just splitting the load evenly for right now, even though that's probably not what is happening.
So 1250 kilograms, so I should be able to do that math, but I'm just going to pull up a calculator to make my life easier.
E, K divided by 4, alright, 30,062.5 Newtons, okay.
Alright, okay.
So theoretically the pre-check says that's all good, cool, okay.
We're not going to generate, we're just going to go to the previewer.
We'll see what happens now when we have basically the preserved geometry and the fixed and the loads set where they are right now.
Interesting.
So it looks like it is building material...
It looks like it's building some material underneath, so we might want to make a body underneath this to just specify, hey, don't build in this space.
In fact, is it? Actually, interesting, is it building inside of this as well? It is.
Okay, so we're going to have to specify some things inside of these.
Hey, let me know when you have a moment.
Okay, give me one second, I'm just still kind of observing the preview.
Um...
Yeah, okay, so we're going to have to add in some extra bodies just to specify some obstacles, but the rest of it looks fine from a preview standpoint, so I'm not super concerned about that yet.
Okay, I am free, what did you want to ask me about?
My assumptions for the obstacle geometry are that I need to... the only things I care about are preserving the connections of the bracket, so the connection at the damper, the connection at the engine connectors, those need to be free of material, essentially.
We don't want material to generate inside of those, because then we won't be able to place our connectors, our bolts inside, so that is my main assumption.
And then as we sort of regenerate previews, we can see if there's other areas where maybe we need to remove... we need to specify more bodies to remove material from, or things like that.
Okay, sounds good.
Um, just off of that actually then, what I'll do for now, we'll... at least we've set up a preliminary study, you know, we can come back afterwards once we kind of see...